patching GrandMA3 is easy when your show and
everything is planned out so you can patch it in
descending order but sometimes you'll encounter a
lighting rig where the fixtures are not patched in
a smart order this video is actually inspired from
a question i received in the comment section from
Gkats5513 from Athens in Greece and it says
great video thank you what if you can't patch
the fixtures in groups but need to go viper
aura viper aura etc what's the fastest way to do
that so in this video i'm going to show you three
different ways you can patch your GrandMA3
console so let's get into it in the description
below you can find a onedrive shared folder with
some files in it and the files for this episode
is episode 19 and as you can see we have a
2d plane we have a patch by spot we have patch
by universe 1 and we have patch by universe 2.
so for the first one we need to go into our
2d plan right here and if we select then
you can see exactly how many fixtures you
need to to put into your GrandMA3  console
and in which mode they have to be in so what
i've done here is all my atomics is in mode 4
all my vipers is in the 16-bit standard mode
NOT the extended mode and you can see it uses
26 channels and the Aurasis also in the standard
mode of 14 channels so start by putting that
amount into your console and as you can see that
is what i have done right here so for to be able
to patch this you need to go into to patch by spot
which is the first technique we're going to use
and as you can see right here we have 301
through 304 is on universe 1. so let's
find all our atomics they're all down here and we
need 301 through 304 so we simply select them here
and we right click and we say they need to be
patched at 1.297 so we simply patch to 1.297
please so you can see we just patched our first
fixtures now we look for the next thing that
goes into universe number one that is Mac Auras 601
through 610 so we find all our auras 601 and we
go all the way down to 610 right here we right
click and we say it need to be on universe 1.157
universe 1.157 please and now we need to
find all our vipers they are 701 through 706
so we find them down here 701 through to 706.
and we right click and we patch them at 1.1
so that's basically the first universe this
is the technique we know this is kind of slow
kind of tedious it's a way of doing it we just
patched one universe right now and we did it the
old-fashioned way so this is the normal way of
patching a GrandMA3  show in a minute i'll show
you technique number two which is very easy to do
and can be used if the fixtures are planned out
in a more random order just like the one i just
showed you but before we get into that if you
have learned something so far be sure to give this
video a thumbs up this gives me some free support
and indicates to youtube that it should spread
out to more people and subscribe to the channel
is definitely a good option so you don't miss any
future episodes from this channel in the future
so let's look at patch technique number two i have
deleted the patch we just made and now i'll show
you technique number two to patch the GrandMA3
show file this time we go back into the shared
folder we find the the file called patch by
universe1 we open it up and as you can see here
this time all the fixtures are sorted in
the order of the patch everything is from
universe 1 and it starts at 1 and goes all the
way down so what we have here is 701 through 706
so basically what we need to do is go over
here again and say 701 through 706. we take
them over here and we start with number one
we go all the way down to six and then we just
leave it like that what else do we need now 601
through 610 we go over here and take this small
little one over here and we move all the way
up into we find unit fixture or sorry fixture
601 we press down and hold down CTRL on your
keyboard and then you mark 601 all the way down
to 610 like this we release and then we find
the last ones which is 301 through 304 once again
we move this little one all the way down be
sure not to scroll on your mouse because then
it's going to forget the selection order
you have right now so 301 through 304 once
again we press down and hold CTRL and we
select all the way down to number four
we release and that's it now we have selected
everything in the right order as you can see
right now so what we need to do now is right click
here and say where do we want to start we want to
start at 1.1 so we patch to 1.1 please and now
we patched the entire universe with only one
single little click and as you can see here the
last atomic address is 309 and right here it's
309 so this is basically how technique number two
works you simply select them in the right order
all of them and you don't use your scroller you
simply use this one up here to to go up and down
you select the one you press control you select
and then you right click and patch them that is
technique number two in a minute i'll show you
technique number three to patching your GrandMA3
console so be sure to stick around for that
and please leave a comment below if you have
anything on your mind i can tell you i had many
discussions in the comments section with you guys
already and it's really motivating for me to know
that someone is watching and sometimes i can even
help you with some GrandMA3  related questions
if you get stuck with something so please let
me hear from you in the comment section and if
you're looking at getting some GrandMA3
hardware yourself i have a bunch of links in the
description where you can have a good look at them
you can see the different models and you can go
in and study each of them so you know how they're
configured and what model would be the right fit
for you the last GrandMA3 -patch technique i'll
show you is probably the fastest if you have a
patch sheet in front of you and this is basically
the way we used to do it on whole hog consoles
and and different other models as well so let's
let's get right into that once again we select all
our patch here we right click and we say on patch
and now we have everything in here there's
nothing patched but we have all our fixtures as we
as we did before so this time we're simply going
to close the patch we're going to save and exit
and we are going to use the command line so
if we have the patch sheet in front of us
you can see that it is the same sheet patch by
universe we have spot number 701 through 706 and
and so forth this time we're going
to use the command line and we have
the command line right here in front of us
so basically we're just going to say patch
fixture and we say 701 through 706 plus
601 through 610 plus 301 through 304 and we say
enter and it's going to ask us where do you
want to patch it we simply say patch to 1.1
please and it exits the patch again and we're
done so right now if we open the patch up
you will see that everything is patched
the way we wanted it on universe number one
so this is basically the fastest way you
can patch it and it's also a little bit
dangerous so be careful in here because if
you patch something to the wrong address
it's gonna warn you but still working in the patch
it gives you maybe a bit better clarity over what
you what it is you're doing i hope this video
gives you a better understanding of the GrandMA3
patch techniques and as maybe you can see
the benefit in all three different kinds of
of techniques i mean sometimes you'll use one
sometimes you use the other and that's fine
if you are interested in being a better GrandMA3  programmer make sure you watch this next video
and please follow along on your granny may on
pc at home watching someone program GrandMA3
is fine but doing it yourself will help
you remember when you need it in real life i
release one video every week on this channel so be
sure to subscribe and click the little bell icon
if you don't want to miss the next episode
you'll be notified when we release new content
i hope to see you on the channel again in the
future and until then happy GrandMA3 programming